# Parth Dangroshiya

#### WEB DEVELOPER



A solution-driven web developer is adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment and finding solutions. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Good knowledge of the best practices for web design, user experience, and speed.

patelparth31795@gmail.com

"Uma Ashish", Aditya park-4, opp. Balaji Hall, 150ft Ring Road, Rajkot - 360004

078740 33053

# **Programming Skills**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C, C++

Tailwind CSS, MaterialUI

React.js, Next.js, React-Toolkit

**TypeScript** 

MongoDB, Firebase

Git and Github

Windows/Linux

### **Project Details**

### **Basic E-Commerce Web Application**

 Made basic e-commerce website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript implementing feather of data store in local storage, filtering as well as searching. registration form with validation.

#### **CRUD Application**

 Made CRUD Operation using React-redux toolkit and MaterialUI. create a basic registration form then show data in a table and store it in a local store. also implementing of edit as well as deleting data.

#### **React Table**

 create React Table Application getting data from JSON place holder API using fetch API and React Table Library then store data in Table. implementing feature of pagination, filtering, check mark, get table row data, column filtering, global filtering, etc.

### **MERN Complete Authentication**

 create mern authentication application using JWT(JSON web token), nodemailer, and bcrypt.
create a signup and login page that data stored in the MongoDB database using express.js, also read data from MongoDB, and show it web page using react.js

#### **React Form Submission**

Create React Basic Form using React Formik with Yup validation. checking different scenarios and adding features of upload single and multiple files. also applying the same task using the React-Hook-Form package.

### Work experience

Since August 2021

#### React Developer

Green Apex Technolabs Ahmedabad

- Identified web-based user interactions and developed highly-responsive user Interface Components via React concepts
- Translated designs into high-quality code and wrote application interface code via JavaScript following React.js workflows.
- Developed the latest user-facing features using React.js and built reusable components & front-end libraries for future use.
- Worked on end-to-end design and development of audiovideo, ecosystem, and e-commerce web applications using react.js and next.js

From October 2019 to August 2020

#### Software developer

GreekSoft Technology Pvt.Ltd Gandhinagar, India

I have developed Trading Software Create Tool Bar, Menu Bar, context Menu, property Sheet, combo Box, Edit Control, Grid Control, Tree Control, List Control, List Box and Docking control, etc. using third party Software Also Apply validation and Property in Dialog Base, Multi-Document and Single Document Application.

From 2017 to 2018

### **QA Engineer**

Pandav Technology Pvt.Ltd Ahmedabad, India

- Pandav Technology Pvt. Ltd is the undisputed leader in the Biometric & RFID industry in India.
- Fingerprint scanner and IRIS sensors are the primary product of Pandav Technology Pvt Ltd.

## **Professional Training:**

From September 2020 to July 2021

#### Web Developer

**Udemy** Online

I learned HTML, CSS, JS, and Bootstrap, etc. I also learned how to make a website responsive design, data converted to Ajax and JSON format without loading webpage, and also data store into local storage.

From 2018 to 2019

### **Embedded Engineering**

Vector India Pvt. Ltd. Bangalore

I trained as Embedded system (Embedded C programming, Linux/ Unix, OS concept, DS concept,8051 assemblies, and Embedded C programming AVR controllers, basic of ARM, basic RTOS, TCP-IP Network programming, Electronics hardware, and software) as well as Lab Assistant at vector institute.

### Education

From 2014 to 2017

Electronics and Communication (CGPA 6.3) U. V. Patel College of Engineering Mahesana

From 2011 to 2014

Electronics and Communication (CGPA 6.8) R. K. University Rajkot